Curriculum Vitae

Personal Details

Name: Felix Ledóchowski

Address: Zirkusgasse 19/14, 1020

Vienna

Nationality: Austrian

Telephone: +43 680/133 26 08

Email: felix@ledochowski.at

Birth Date: 05.05.1992

Driver's License: Full Austrian Class B license

Website: felixledochowski.github.io



Software engineer with 5 years of professional experience in Desktop, Virtual Reality, mobile and console development in Unreal Engine and Unity. Developed and released multiple mobile, desktop and console applications created in Unity, Unreal Engine 4 and 5. Experienced in creating scalable applications for smart phones, Meta Quest, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series and PC. Deep understanding of the Gameplay Ability System, Common UI, Enhanced Input, Material system, Niagara, Unreal Insights, plugins, etc. Experienced in working in a large team and solo development. Capable of quickly delivering prototypes. Completed Masters of Media Informatics with distinction.

Personal Profile

Languages:	German (native), English (fluent)
I.T. skills:	Programming skills in Unreal Engine 4 & 5, Gameplay Ability System, Common UI,
	Enhanced Input, Material system, Niagara, Unreal Insights, plugins, Blueprints, C++, C#,
	Unity, Java, GML, CSS/HTML, SQL, JavaScript, Blender, Matlab.
	Experienced with developing applications for Android, iOS, Windows, Meta Quest, Xbox
	Series, PS5. Microsoft Office suite
Personal Interests:	Video game development, Mobile development, Virtual Reality, input systems, innovative use of known hardware.
	use of known hardware.

Curriculum Vitae

Work experience

June 2024 – Present	Full Time employment at ViewApp Tasks: Lead UI/UX developer, implementation of new UI elements using Common UI and Enhanced Input, input calibrator for any input device, certification requirements for Xbox and PlayStation, C++ game logic and save system, collaboration with internal and external team. Communications with publisher. Developing on Xbox and PlayStation development kits.
April 2024 – June 2024	Project based work at VRisch Tasks: Development of an AR experience for Meta Quest Pro, using a custom built engine by Meta. Creation of hand tracking based interaction system and UI. Procedural generation of level based on scene setup in AR. Technical artist tasks such as producing efficient materials, portal effect, Niagara particle systems, mesh optimization and testing performance using Unreal Insights.
September 2023 –	Personal development
April 2024	Creation of a project on Meta Quest 2, featuring an innovative, VR Sickness free control scheme. Improving skills using Unreal Engine 5.
2019 - 2023	Full Time employment as Software Developer at SquareBytes Tasks: Unreal Engine 4 and 5 development using C++ and Blueprints. Development and release of multiple mobile real estate applications featuring augmented reality, 3D navigation, DLC download and real time data fetching. Development of VR applications featuring hand tracking and multiplayer. Development of real estate applications capable of responsively scaling from mobile, tablets, PC all the way to 4K multi touch tables. Some experience in developing applications using Kinect.
March - May 2017	Internship at Interactive Media Systems Tasks: Improving Tracking performance for a VR solution in C++
July - September 2016	Temporary Employment at Novomatic Gaming Industries Game Studio 1 Tasks: Developing a GUI in C++ and SFML for testing new concepts Developing a tool in C# for creating XMLs for Interface Supporting the Design Team with technical problems
July & August 2013:	Internship at Misys Tasks: Database management using SQL & Excel, Customer Relations
November 2010 - August 2011:	Civil Service at Haus Malta (retirement home) Tasks: I.T. support, Elderly care
July & August 2010:	Internship at the I.T. Department of the Austrian Chambers of Commerce: Tasks: Developing Excel tools (models/macros), On-site service, Tutorial creation
Education	
2016 - September 2023	MSc in Media Informatics at the Vienna University of Technology Focus on Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality and Game Development (Passed with distinction)
2010 - 2016:	BSc in Media Informatics and Visual Computing at the Vienna University of Technology
2008:	Term abroad: Dublin, Ireland St. Killian School
2002 –2010:	Secondary School: Schottengymnasium Vienna Austria

FELIX LEDÓCHOWSKI

Vienna, Austria

Zirkusgasse 19/14, 1020 Vienna +43 680/133 26 08, felix@ledochowski.at